Casper van Battum • CV

CREATIVE PROGRAMMER - I want to create as many different ways as I can for others to experience, discover and express themselves about the world that we live in, and build on what make us human.



Birthdate: April 23, 1998 Email: cvanbattum@gmail.com

ü

Place of residence: Den Hoorn, Netherlands

Phone: +31 6 10 26 78 20



Address: Oranjelaan 16, 2635JL Website: cvanbattum.com

Language proficiency: Dutch (native C2), English (full C2), French (conversational B1/B2)



Education

2018-today Game Development at HKU Utrecht School of the Arts

- Followed courses such as C++ Advanced, Environmental Modelling, Networking, Maths for Games, AI for Games, and done numerous projects.
- Learning to create games and interactive experiences from an artistic, designer and technological viewpoint.
- See my portfolio for a curated overview of the work I made at the HKU.

2016-2017 Computer Science at Delft University of Technology

- Followed courses such as Calculus, Algorithms & Data Structures, Discrete Mathematics, and Computer Organisation.
- Stopped after the first year because the program didn't satisfy me creatively.

2010-2016 High school • Nature & Technology track • VWO grade

- Followed courses such as Informatics, Additional Maths, Fine Arts, Chemistry, and Physics.
- Final research project: Simulation of the impact of a water droplet on a solid surface.

Work experience

2021 Delivery driver at **Picnic BV.**

• Delivery driver for an online grocery store.

2019-today High school tutor with Bijlesnetwerk BV.

- Tutor in maths, ICT and programming.
- I've had about seven different students.

2017-2018 Lab Assistant at Brightsight BV.

• Supporting the development and construction of research equipment, help with moving the company, and designing new tools.

Volunteer experience

Since 2017 Active contributor to the OpenStreetMap project

- Mapping missing details around the places I live and visit.
- Keeping local information up to date.
- Contributing to armchair mapping across the world (most notably Canada).
- Associate member of the OpenStreetMap Foundation.

2015-2017 Volunteer teacher at CoderDojo Delft

• Weekly event organized by a group of volunteers to teach kids aged 7-14 programming in Scratch, Python or JavaScript.

Other experiences

2018, 2019 Workaway exchange in Norway (2 mo) and France (2 wk)

- Cultural exchange for food and shelter and exchange of skills.
- Stayed at three addresses so far, on two separate trips.
- Helped renovating buildings in Norway and in France, helped as a farmhand in Norway.

Hobbies, skills and other interests

Photography (since 2014)

- Capturing landscape, nature, street, and travel photos.
- Photo editing with Adobe Lightroom & Photoshop.

Programming (since 2013)

• Used languages as BASIC, Java, Javascript, Typescript, C/C++, C#, Python, PHP5, SQL, and more.

Gaming

• I enjoy simulator, building and strategy games as well as story or emotion-driven single player games.

Hiking and backpacking

- Hiked several long-distance trails, such as the Tour du Mont Blanc and the GR54 in France.
- I like going places you couldn't otherwise reach, at times you couldn't otherwise be there.

Travel

• Exploring other places and cultures from close by is a major source of creative inspiration.